Guide to the Yung Kwai Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yung Kwai papers
1874-1939
1874-1894
MS 1795
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
The papers consist of professional files; genealogical materials; photographs and memorabilia; and writings and translations documenting Yung Kwai's participation in the Chinese Educational Mission, his diplomatic career with the Chinese Legation, as well as his personal life.
Yung, Kwai, 1861-1943
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dana Young, 2001.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by type of material.
Biographical / Historical
Yung Kwai was born on March 2, 1861, in Sin Hui, Province of Kwangtung, China. He came to the United States as a participant in the Chinese Educational Mission program, studying at the Springfield, Massachusetts, High School. He subsequently enrolled in Yale College from which he received his B.A. degree in 1884. From 1884 to 1885 he was employed by the Chinese Legation in Washington, D.C. He returned to Yale during the 1885-1886 academic year to study at the Sheffield Scientific School, and the next year at the Columbia University School of Mines. In 1890 he joined the Chinese Legation in Washington, D.C. and served successively as interpreter, first secretary, adviser, and chargé d'affaires ad interim until his retirement in 1936. On May 23, 1894, he married Mary Elizabeth Lyon Burnham. He was also a reporter for the New York Herald, 1893-1897. Following his retirement from the legation, he served as general adviser to the Chinese Embassy, Washington, D.C., from 1936 to 1943. Yung Kwai died on March 17, 1943, in Washington, D.C.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of professional files; genealogical materials; photographs and memorabilia; and writings and translations documenting Yung Kwai's participation in the Chinese Educational Mission, his diplomatic career with the Chinese Legation, as well as his personal life.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
China -- Foreign relations -- United States; United States -- Foreign relations -- China; Yung, Kwai, 1861-1943; Chinese Educational Commission; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1884
- Inventory
  - Diplomatic career [documents pertaining to the Chinese Legation] (Box 1, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Personal papers/documents in Chinese
    - Chinese Educational Mission
      - Autograph books, 1874, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Handwritten memoir about the mission, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - The Chinese Educational Mission and Its Influence [Yung Shang Him], 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Yale Class Day Program, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Constitution of the Societas Condita Causa Augendarum Rerum Chinesium Christiana, [1878?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Curriculum vitae [in Yung Kwai's handwriting], undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Genealogical documents [in Chinese], undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Name cards [in English and Chinese], undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Passenger list souvenir, Pacific Mail Steamship "Mongolia", 1908 November (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wedding invitation and announcement, "at home" card, marriage certificate, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Writings/translations
    - Manuscripts of original essays (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Demosthenes", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Springfield High School graduation address, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Civil Service Reform", 1880 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Winter Homes and Habits of Animals", 1880 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "The Cabinet of Washington", 1880 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "My Summer Vacation", 1880 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Opium in China", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "The Chinese Question", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "The Chinese Bill", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Nihilism", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Lincoln and Garfield", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - An Exposition of Confucianism, Prepared for the Parliament of Religions [by Pung Kwang Yu, translated by Yung Kwai], 1893 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - An Exposition of Confucianism [handwritten translation includes sections not printed in 1893], undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Our Youth [issues with articles by Yung Kwai] (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - New Year - The Chinese Holiday, 1889 March (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - "Worship of Ancestors", 1889 April (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - "Social Customs Among the Chinese", 1889 September (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - "Chinese Food", 1889 November (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Teaching from Pictures for Young and Old [by Janet Byrne, translated by Yung Kwai, some entries in handwriting of Burnham Yung Kwai], 1886 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Typescripts of unpublished (?) translations
      - "Anecdotes of Confucius", undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - "Yulan", undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Letter from Sunyowe Päng [declines request to illustrate a story], 1902 November (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Oversize
    - Edict from the Chinese government to Guatemala [includes yellow silk wrapper], undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Family scrapbook, 1877-1894 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Photographs of the children of Tong Shao-Yi and Yung Kwai; large group of Chinese officials and students, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Star and Sash of the "Order of Jia He" [also called "Star of the Golden Grain"], undated (Box 6, Folder 26)